#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/anupagaire

## Top Skills

Python JavaScript SQL

#### Certifications

pandas Essential Training

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

# **Anupa Gaire**

Python Developer | AWS Certified Kathmandu

## Summary

An experienced Python developer with 5+ years of experience specializing in web backend development, with a strong background in developing, deploying, and maintaining complex web applications. Expertise includes Python, Django, Flask, JavaScript, SQL, data processing, and cloud technologies such as AWS (EC2, Lambda, S3, etc.). Experienced in Agile environments and committed to ensuring the stability and performance of web applications.

## Experience

Verisk Software Engineer September 2021 - Present (11 months) Kathmandu, Bāgmatī, Nepal

- -Developed web-based applications in a team of 7 for analytics, ML model utilization, and data processing tasks, contributing to complex web applications' stability and performance.
- -Utilized **Python** (Flask) and **JavaScript** (Angular) for backend development.
- -Involved in **text mining** and analysis of PDF documents, optimizing algorithms and improving the data processing pipelines.
- -Worked with **AWS services** (EC2, Lambda, S3, SQS), ensuring high scalability and reliability of applications in production.
- -Collaborated with team members to ensure high code quality using **Git** and best practices.

### Tekvortex

Software Engineer

November 2019 - September 2021 (1 year 11 months)

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Involved in a team of ten for a web content archiving platform as a contractor for Smarsh Inc.
- The archiving platform entailed a scaled web content crawling and

processing engine, an in-house built scheduling system, a diversified archiving process, optimized searching, and exports on demand.

- Worked with technologies like tasks queuing and scheduling, batch processing, webcontent proxying, searching, reporting,

scripting etc.

 Contributed to converting the core monolithic application to numerous

isolated distributed services with a centralized data store.

- Deployed and maintained applications in on-premise dev and QA environments

Smart Solutions
Python Developer
November 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 3 months)
Kathmandu, Nepal

- Backend developer involved in development of application featuring data collection, aggregation and analysis.
- Contributed to the development of backend services for data collection, aggregation, and analysis, utilizing **Python** and **Django**.
- R&D contribution, Architecture brainstorming for solutions to application related problems
- Server-side/API development in Python, data visualization and analysis
- Involvement in product release and deployment

3Hammers Pvt. Ltd.
Web Developer
June 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 4 months)
Kathmandu, Nepal

- Worked in a web development team for an E-commerce project.
- Contributed in new features and enhanced the existing features using
- Python (django), jQuery and MySQL

## Education

Tribhuvan University

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering · (October 2013 - October 2017)

Little Angel's College 10 + 2, Science · (2011 - 2013)

Little Angels High School High School · (2010)